Manish Kumar

23 Van Wagenen Ave, Apt# 2, Jersey City, NJ 07306 USA | Email: mkumar001@my.wilmu.edu | Phone: +1 551-229-2663

Profile Summary

I am a software professional with an industrial experience mainly focusing on AngularJS, UI Development and Java technologies. I have also worked extensively on software testing, scripting languages, maintenance and implementation based on existing software. Prior to my work experience, I have done a coursework based Masters degree with broad ranging courses in computer science. I consider myself a hard working and detail oriented professional with strong analytical and critical thinking abilities.

Education

Wilmington University, Delaware

Jan 2016 - Dec 2018

Masters of Science, Information Systems Technologies

Skills

Web Development: Angular JS, Angular 2/4/6/7/8/9/10/11, Express.js, jQuery, Javascript, Javascript framework, ECMAScript ES5/ES6+, Ember.js, Next.js, Vue.js Web API, CSS/CSS3/Sass, Semantic, Bootstrap, HTML/HTML5, REST API, Swagger, Node.js/NPM, Webpack

Databases: Microsoft SQL, Oracle PL/SQL, MogoDB

Languages: Shell Scripting, Visual Basic, Assembly Language, Python, PHP

Methodologies: OOP/D, UML, MVC

Others: Adobe Flash, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD/illustrator, Visual Studio, MS Project, GitHub, Docker, Grunt & Gulp, Protractor, NPM,

native DOM, Event APIs

Professional Experience

Bank of America, Jersey City, NJ

June 2020 – Current

UI/Web Developer

- Responsible for analyzing, mocking and giving shaping UI design as desire and implement it using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery/JavaScript, AngularJS.
- Performing test execution on SIT and UAT server using real time data.
- Working closely with the User Experience Designer, performing optimized tests to increase conversion and user engagement.

Dun & Bradstreet, Center Valley, PA (https://www.iresearch.dnb.com)

Jan 2019 – June 2020

UI/Web Developer

- Responsible for developing new user-facing features along with building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Responsible for writing and executing TDD and BDD based automation scripts for UI end to end testing using ES6, Protractor, Selenium and Cucumber for automation testing.
- Responsible for mocking and giving shaping front-end as desire using HTML, CSS, ¡Query/JavaScript, AngularJS.
- Presented an architecture for upgrading Angularis 1.9 to Angular 11 using hybrid approach.

Anthem Inc, Norfolk, VA

Aug 2018 – Dec 2018

UI/Front-End Developer

- Responsible for developing SPA by writing well-structured, easily maintainable and well-documented code using HTML 5.0, CSS3, SCSS, jQuery, AngularJS and JavaScript and jQuery
- Utilized AngularJS to bind HTML template to JavaScript object & performed Parent & Activity provider UI designs, from concept through final product release for web and mobile applications in responsive design.
- Created Custom Directives, filters in AngularJS, made use of Modules, Filters and \$http service from controller.

SQA Labs, Glendale, AZ

April 2018 – July 2018

UI Developer/UX Designer

- Developed prototype concepts using Axure, Photoshop, and Illustrator concept designs.
- Developed new prototypes and implemented those prototypes using JavaScript, jQuery, HTML and CSS.
- Responsible for creating JavaScript code for different modules.

Perseverance Software's Pvt. Ltd, India (http://perseverance.in/)

Jan 2014 - Jan 2016

UI/UX Designer (Web Developer)

- Responsible for designing, maintaining and updating website using JavaScript, J-query, PHP and HTML, bootstrap.
- Designed user-centered Web sites with sophisticated production values and intuitive navigation to maximize user engagement.
- Managed usability testing for site landing pages in preparation for Web site redesign.